Chad Schroeder

Senior Front End Developer

A 2412 Palmetto Ave #4, Pacifica, California 94044

M 925.428.3596

E gmchad@gmail.com

About Me

I am a Senior Front End Developer with 14+ years of experience working with UI and visual designers to build pixel-perfect, interactive interfaces and websites. Exceptional ability to communicate technical concepts to non-technical audiences and directly consult with clients. Experience supervising junior developers and remote development teams. Solid problem-solving skills, wellorganized, self-motivated, able to meet tight deadlines and handle multiple projects. A passion for semantic markup, web accessibility and bridging the gap between code technologies and design.

Professional Skills

FIOIESSIOIIai Skiiis	
HTML 5 Semantic markup	Back End
Web accessibility	Wordpress / Drupal
Responsive emails	MySQL
Search engine optimization	Tools
CSS 3	Git
SASS	Gulp
Bootstrap / Material Design	Sketch
SVG and CSS animation	Zeplin
JavaScript ES6 React AngularJS HandlebarsJS jQuery	Photoshop VS Code / Sublime
Education	

Education

Cal State Long Beach 1992 - 1995

International Security and Conflict Resolution

Fullerton Community College 1989 - 1992

General Studies

Work Experience

Senior Front End Developer

Dec 2015 - Apr 2018

DesignMap • San Francisco, California

- Produced UI component libraries, responsive layouts, javascript applications and high-fidelity prototypes for client websites and enterprise software using HTML, CSS, ES6, React, AngularJS, jQuery and HandlebarsJS.
- · Participated in early discovery of code expectations and advised throughout the UX lifecycle to ensure rapid development that delivered to client needs.
- Supervised junior developers and coordinated with remote development teams in code production.

Front End Developer

Feb 2014 - Dec 2015

DesignMap • San Francisco, California

- Collaborated with visual designers to convert design comps into production-ready code for websites and interfaces for enterprise software.
- Built high-fidelity prototypes in AngularJS for A/B user testing and proof-of-concept projects.
- · Produced UI component libraries and responsive layouts as front end deliverables for software teams.
- Built and tested responsive emails for company and client marketing.

Web Developer

Jan 2013 - Feb 2014

Freelance • San Francisco, Calfiornia

- Converted design comps into mobile-first, responsive production code for a variety of company websites.
- · Built high-fidelity prototypes in AngularJS.
- Coded responsive emails for marketing campaigns.
- · Developed company websites in Wordpress and PHP.

Front End Developer

Nov 2011 - Dec 2012

Anthem Worldwide • San Francisco, California

- · Converted design comps into responsive websites.
- Developed company and client product presences in Wordpress and Drupal.

Web Developer

Sep 2009 - Nov 2011

Freelance • Southern California

· Worked with design teams to convert Photoshop comps into front end production code and online services for a variety of consumer websites.